<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="exhibits">
        <item>Enchanted Forest: Festival of Trees</item>
        <item>Cultural History of the Mid-South</item>
        <item>Natural History of the Mid-South</item>
        <item>The Mansion</item>
        <item>Lemoyne-Owen College: A Beacon of Hope</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="exhibit_details">
        <item>
            Open November 18 - December 31, 2017

            Admission to the Enchanted Forest does not include regular Museum admission.
            Ticket prices:
            Adults: $6
            Children/Seniors: $5

            Festival of Trees
            Beautiful trees decorated by professional designers, individuals and local organizations sparkle on the mezzanine.

            Gingerbread Village
            A snow-covered village of scrumptious creations awaits you! From cozy cottages to majestic mansions, all are designed by local chefs, businesses, individuals and groups.

            Model Train and Christmas Village
            A miniature train twists and turns throughout a snow-covered village, inspiring the imagination of children and adults alike.

            Pictures with Santa
            November 18  –  December 24
            Photo packages: $10 – $60
            Photos courtesy of J&amp;B Childress Portrait Art
            www.jandbchildress.com

            Enchanted Forest Fridays
            Dec. 1, 8, 15 &amp; 22 9am to 9pm
            The Enchanted Forest is even more magical at night!
            Visit when the sun goes down and see how the trees sparkle and shine!
        </item>
        <item>
            Pardon our dust, we are moving some exhibits! The Piggly Wiggly, Country Store and Circus are unavailable for viewing. The Pink Palace Mansion, along with three iconic exhibits, is under renovation. When the Mansion reopens in June 2018, the Piggly Wiggly replica, the Country Store and the Clyde Parke Miniature Circus will all be on display inside the Mansion.

            In the Pink Palace’s Cultural Exhibits, a huge array of artifacts and dioramas invite you to explore our city’s past.

            The First Americans, butcher marks on a mastodon bone tell of a successful Paleolithic hunt. An extraordinary collection of finely crafted tools and Native American pottery are remnants of a complex civilization on the Mississippi. Mystical hunchback figures, grim disembodied human heads, and whimsical animal effigies, all carefully buried with the dead, reflect the spiritual beliefs of this mysterious culture.

            The History of Memphis, 1800-1900 tells the story of Memphis from its birth as a frontier river town to its emergence as a vital Victorian Era city. Slavery and emancipation, disease and medicine, privilege and persecution are all brought to life through objects of both everyday life and extraordinary events. See Memphis housing from a reconstructed frontier cabin to an opulent Victorian music room  An horrific battle diorama forms the centerpiece of the Civil War gallery.  Thomas Harwell’s “mummy casket,” in its darkened alcove, represents an archeological mystery solved, while a mail coach, private buggy and public omnibus evoke the era of horse-drawn transportation.
        </item>
        <item>
            A great diversity of mammals once inhabited our region…

            The first floor of the museum describes the natural history of the Mid-south. This area, within a 200 mile area radius of Memphis, encompasses several major environments including the channels and oxbow lakes of the Mississippi River and its tributaries, their associated floodplains; the sand hills of western Tennessee and northern Mississippi, and the nearby highlands of the Ouachita and Ozark Mountains in Arkansas and the Highland Rim of Central Tennessee.

            The exhibits open with “Adaptations”, a large collection of skulls and skeletons of all types of animals. The display explains how the placement of teeth, horns and antlers, and eyes as well as body shapes show how animals have evolved to adapt to their environment.

            The formation and biological history of lakes formed when the Mississippi River changes course to leave a water-filled abandoned channel behind, is described in the “Oxbow Lake” exhibit. These small crescent-shaped lakes are frequently found in eastern Arkansas and western Mississippi and are famous for duck hunting and fishing. Three dioramas show the rich variety of life found in them.

            The most common animals found in our area are featured in the “Insect” exhibit. Two large displays of butterflies and moths show the difference between large and colorful tropical insects and their small, duller relatives living in the Mid-south. Visitors learn how insects communicate and the tremendous variation in insect sizes and shapes occurring in the Memphis area.

            A large exhibit on “Geology” shows how mountains and oceans were formed and how the movement of huge rock plates on the surface of the earth create mountains and ocean basins. Earthquakes, so frequent in the Mid-south, are explained and a real seismograph recorder shows the vibrations constantly occurring in our area. Spectacular examples of the rocks and minerals of Tennessee, Arkansas, and Southern Illinois, along with minerals found all over the world are exhibited. The remainder of the exhibits shows the history of life over the past 600 million years emphasizing hundreds of fossil specimens found in Tennessee, Arkansas, and Mississippi.
        </item>
        <item>
            Piggly Wiggly founder Clarence Saunders began building his 36,500 square foot dream house in 1922. He wanted a home "Memphis would be proud of, a real Southern showplace," and he wanted all materials, contractors and even the architect to be Southern.

            Memphis architect Hubert T. McGee designed a home built of pink Georgian marble, featuring a pipe organ, ballroom, indoor swimming pool, shooting gallery and bowling alley.

            Sadly, Saunders never got to sleep in his dream home. He lost a battle with the New York Stock Exchange in 1923 and went bankrupt, losing his fortune and his unfinished mansion, which was then donated to the city of Memphis.

            The city spent $150,000 to complete the building and landscape the grounds.  The impressive lobby was finished with marble floors, walls and stairs, and a marble fireplace bearing the city’s seal was installed in an adjacent room, which would have been Saunders’ living room.

            Perhaps the most striking details in the lobby, however, are the stuffed polar bear and the murals painted by Burton Callicot, which hang as the only remaining example of W.P.A. art in Memphis.
        </item>
        <item>
            Now open!

            LeMoyne-Owen College has been a central institution in Memphis since its founding in 1871 as the LeMoyne Normal and Commercial School. Over the years the college has educated generations of teachers, professionals and public servants. This exhibit explores LeMoyne-Owen’s unique past as a Historically Black College as well as a vital part of the Memphis community by considering the institution’s academics and athletics, students’ participation in the city’s civil rights movement, and the impact of notable alumni.

            Focusing on:

            -Athletics

            -Art

            -Academics

            -Campus life (including Greek life)

            -Notable alumni
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <array name="exhibit_picture">
        <item>@drawable/enchanted</item>
        <item>@drawable/cultural_midsouth</item>
        <item>@drawable/bison</item>
        <item>@drawable/mansion</item>
        <item>@drawable/lemoyne</item>
    </array>
    <array name="map_picture">
        <item>@drawable/museum_map1</item>
        <item>@drawable/museum_map2</item>
        <item>@drawable/mansion_map</item>
    </array>
</resources>